<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Alex Day</title><link>https://www.alexday.me/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Alex Day</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 22:24:55 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.alexday.me/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iCal2Notion</title><link>https://www.alexday.me/projects/ical2notion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 22:24:55 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.alexday.me/projects/ical2notion/</guid><description>Earlier this year I decided that I needed some sort of hub for the tasks and events in my life. I decided at that point to go with Notion (although I have now switched to org-mode in emacs). One feature that notion is lacking is the ability to pull in events from Google Calendar into a database. I noticed that there were no tools that did this so I decided to roll my own.</description></item><item><title>Python Docstring</title><link>https://www.alexday.me/projects/python-docstring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 17:41:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.alexday.me/projects/python-docstring/</guid><description>Emacs Emacs is an incredibly extensible editor. It is one of the two major players in the unix &amp;#34;poweruser&amp;#34; editor wars. It is both configured and extended in elisp, an emacs-specific dialect of lisp. The main benefit I see of using Emacs is how I can easily add functionality I find that I need.
Python Docstring At work currently I am writing a lot of python.</description></item><item><title>Emoji Summarization</title><link>https://www.alexday.me/projects/emoji/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.alexday.me/projects/emoji/</guid><description>For my senior year capstone project at Clarion University I worked with another student to try and summarize sentences by producing a string of emojis. We accomplished this goal through the use of vector embeddings. The initial algorithm is explained in a blog posts, as well as a novel sentence segmentation algorithm that I developed as a consequence of the project. We presented this project at the Penn York conference(slides, abstract) in Clarion and published a paper at the 2020 PACISE conference.</description></item><item><title>Animations</title><link>https://www.alexday.me/projects/animations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.alexday.me/projects/animations/</guid><description>Constellations This is animation is based on the animation found here. However, I wrote this program as an excuse to try out TypeScript so I made it object oriented instead of trying to do it in as few lines as possible. Check it out on GitHub. Collatz Conjecture Visualized This is my take on the Coding Train&amp;#39;s Coding in the Cabana Collatz Conjecture. My version is using Python and the Python P5 library.</description></item><item><title>Bankers Algorithm</title><link>https://www.alexday.me/projects/bankers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.alexday.me/projects/bankers/</guid><description>Banker&amp;#39;s Algorithm implemented in Python3 with a Flask RESTful backend and HTML/Bootstrap/JS front end. The site is hosted on Heroku at http://bankers.alexday.me.
Usage This was a project for the Operating Systems class at Clarion. This project had a specific input file format that is shown on the left hand side of the web app. This format is also shown with comments describing what each line corresponds to below.</description></item><item><title>DSML 4 Kidz</title><link>https://www.alexday.me/projects/dsml/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.alexday.me/projects/dsml/</guid><description>In the summer of 2019 I was lucky enough to be accepted into the University of Arizona&amp;#39;s CATVehicle REU. Over the course of 10 weeks my group mates and I developed a Domain Specific Modeling Language (DSML) aimed at providing a simple interface for 4th grade students to interact with an autonomous vehicle. This language was used to augment a robotics curriculum for over 420 students in the Tucson area.</description></item></channel></rss>